Guide to the Jewish Social Studies: records, 1931-1987
Department of Special Collections
Jewish Social Studies: records,
1931-1987
M0670
57 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Correspondence, manuscripts, financial records, and subscription records, 1934-1987; correspondence pertaining to the Conference on Jewish Relations, 1931-1956; and materials pertaining to the Jewish Cultural Reconstruction.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Historical note
Zipperstein and Aron Rodrigue, associate professor of history, agreed in 1993 to become co-editors of Jewish Social Studies. Founded in 1939, it had been considered the flagship journal in the field ofJewish studies for decades, but was published sporadically after the death in 1990 of the previous editor.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Correspondence, manuscripts, financial records, and subscription records, 1934-1987; correspondence pertaining to the Conference on Jewish Relations, 1931-1956; and materials pertaining to the Jewish Cultural Reconstruction.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Conference on Jewish Relations (U.S.); Conference on Jewish Social Studies (U.S.); Jews--History.; Jewish studies.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1934 - 1944 (Box 1)
- Sociological Conference, 1954 (Box 1)
- Fund Raising Nation Wide, 1966 - 1970 (Box 1)
- Misc. Files, 1955 - 1965 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, A-D, 1950 - 1967 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, D-L, 1950 - 1967 (Box 3)
- Letters, 1962 - 1967 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, M-S, 1947 - 1965 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, T-Z, 1947 - 1965 (Box 5)
- Minutes of Board Meetings, 1936 - 1975 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, 1968 - 1976 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, Authors A-K, 1964 - (Box 6)
- Correspondence, Authors L-Z, 1964 - (Box 7)
- Correspondence, A-R, 1962 - 1976 (Box 7)
- Correspondence, subscriptions, 1962 - 1976 (Box 8)
- Subscriptions and drops, 1970s (Box 8)
- Accounts and financial files (bills, invoices) JCA and LCBC taxes, 1969 - 1979 (Box 9)
- JCA and LCBC taxes (Box 10)
- Accounts and financial files (Box 10)
- Correspondence with reviewers and writers, 1968 - 1973 (Box 10)
- Correspondence with reviewers and writers, 1968 - 1973 (Box 11)
- M.I.P.C. files 1960s (Box 11)
- Jewish Social Studies reprints (Box 11)
- Bank books (Box 11)
- Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR), correspondence, 1931 - 1939 (Box 11)
- Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR), correspondence, 1931 - 1939 (Box 12)
- Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR), correspondence, 1939 - 1956 (Box 13)
- Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR), correspondence, 1939 - 1956 (Box 14)
- Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR), correspondence, 1939 - 1956 (Box 15)
- Robison census data (Box 16)
- Jewish Cultural Reconstruction material (Box 16)
- Coffenbach Depot Reports (Box 16)
- European periodicals pre World War II (Box 16)
- Documentary history project (Box 16)
- Jewish Cultural Reconstruction material (Box 17)
- Coffenbach Depot Reports (Box 17)
- European periodicals pre World War II (Box 17)
- Documentary history project (Box 17)
- Manuscripts, 1979 - 1985 (Box 18)
- Manuscripts, 1979 - 1985 (Box 19)
- Manuscripts, 1986 - 1987 (Box 20)
- Manuscripts, 1986 - 1987 (Box 21)
- Current manuscripts (Box 22)
- Current manuscripts (Box 23)
- Rejected manuscripts and correspondence (Box 24)
- Rejected manuscripts and correspondence (Box 25)
- Current files, A-Z (Box 26)
- Current files, A-Z (Box 27)
- Current files, 1980s (Box 28)
- Current files, 1980s (Box 29)
- Rejected manuscript correspondence (Box 30)
- Old Jewish Social Studies "stuff" (Box 30)
- Rejected manuscript correspondence (Box 31)
- Old Jewish Social Studies "stuff" (Box 31)
- Old paid bills, receipts, and disbursements (Box 32)
- Subscription Financial Billing and Billing Correspondence,1986 - 1990s (Box 33)
- Subscription Financial Billing and Billing Correspondence,1986 - l990s (Box 34)
- Financial materials, l970s-1985 (Box 35)
- Early subscription books (Box 35)
- Disbursements, 1945 - 1952, 2 v. (Volume 1 & 2)
- Receipts, 1945 - 1958, 2 v. (Volume 3 & 4)
- Checkbooks (Volume 5,6,7,8,9)
- Subscription records (Volume 10)
- Account book (Volume 11)
- Card files (Othertype 12)